Preliminary Guide to the Academic Publications Office records, 1943-1997 RG0034
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Academic Publications Office records
1943-2004
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Graduate Studies and Academic Affairs. Academic Publications
George Washington University. Office of Academic Publications
RG0034
12.75 Linear Feet
The mission of the Academic Publications office is to edit university publications such as the University Bulletin. Materials for this collection include dissertation abstracts, commencement programs (including the Law and Medical School), class schedules, University Bulletins, degrees conferred, President Carroll inauguration, Law School centennial and special convocations, stylistic guidelines, and master course and program data forms. The material ranges in date from 1943 to 2004.
Restrictions on Access
Portions of this collection are unprocessed. Some records may be restricted.Please see Special Collections staff for assistance.
Acquisition Information
These records were transferred to University Archives in 1998 and 2009.
Historical or Biographical Note
Academic Publications reports to the office of Graduate Studies and Academic Affairs, which is a part of the Executive Vice President for Academic Affairs office. The mission of this office is to edit university publications such as the university bulletin.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials for this collection include dissertation abstracts, commencement programs (including the Law and Medical School, class schedules, University Bulletins, degrees conferred, President Carroll inauguration, Law School centennial and special convocations, stylistic guidelines, master course and program data forms, Middle States, GWSolutions, and second-class postage permit filings. The material ranges in date from 1943 to 2004.
Collection Organization
Organized into three series. They include Publications, Stylistic guidelines, and Master Course and Program Data Forms.
Washington (D.C.); Presidents; Inaugurations; Publications; Commencement ceremonies -- Washington (D.C.); George Washington University
- Publications, 1943-1997; RG0034 Series 1; 8 Linear feet (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4, Box 5, Box 6)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of dissertation abstracts, commencement programs (including the Law and Medical School, class schedules, University Bulletins, degrees conferred, President Carroll inauguration, Law School centennial and special convocations. The material ranges in date from 1943-97. They were transferred to University Archives in 1998.
  Formerly ACC#703
  - Dissertation abstracts: A-M, 1959-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Years are approximate
  - Dissertation abstracts: N-Z, 1959-1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dissertation abstracts: A-M, 1986-1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Dissertation abstracts: N-Z, 1986-1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Course bulletins, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Course bulletins, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Course bulletins, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Course bulletins, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Course bulletins, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Course bulletins, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Class schedules, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Class schedules, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Class schedules, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Class schedules, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Class schedules, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Class schedules, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Class schedules, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Faculty handbook, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Commencement: General, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Commencement: General, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Commencement: General, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Commencement: General, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Commencement: General, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Commencement: General, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Commencement: Law, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Commencement: General, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Commencement: Medical, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Commencement: General, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Commencement: Medical, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Commencement: General, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Commencement: Medical, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Commencement: General, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Commencement: Medical, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Commencement: General, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Commencement: General, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Invitations, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Commencement: Medical, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Degrees conferred, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Degrees conferred, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Commencement: General, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Commencement: Medical, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Commencement: Law, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Commencement: General, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Commencement: Law, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Commencement: Medical, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Commencement: General, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Commencement: Law, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Commencement: Medical, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Commencement: General, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Commencement: Law, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Commencement: Medical, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Degrees conferred, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Commencement: Law, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Degrees conferred, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Commencement: General, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Commencement: Law, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Degrees conferred, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Commencement: General, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Commencement: Law, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Degrees Conferred, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Commencement: General, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Commencement: Law, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Degrees conferred, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Commencement: General, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Commencement: Law, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Commencement: Medical, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Degrees conferred, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Commencement: General, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Commencement: Law, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Commencement: Medical, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Degrees conferred, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Honors program, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Commencement: General, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Commencement: Law, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Commencement: Medical, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Degrees conferred, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Honors program, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Commencement: General, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Commencement: Law, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Commencement: Medical, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Commencement: General, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Commencement: General, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Commencement: Law, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Commencement: Medical, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - President Trachtenberg Inauguration, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Commencement: General, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Commencement: Law, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Commencement: Medical, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Commencement: General, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Commencement: Law, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Commencement: Medical, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Honors program, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - President Reagan honors, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Winter convocation, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Hooding ceremony, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Commencement: General, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Commencement: General, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Commencement: General, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Commencement: General, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Commencement: General, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Class schedules, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    Spring semester
  - Class schedules, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    Summer and spring semesters
  - Class schedules, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - President Carroll's Inauguration, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Law School Centennial, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Special convocations, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Commencement programs, 1943-1949 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Commencement programs, 1950-1953 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Commencement programs, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Commencement programs, 1956-1957 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Commencement programs, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Commencement programs, 1960-1961 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Commencement programs, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Commencement programs, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Induction Ceremony, 2011-2013; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - The Centennial convocation of the GWU Law School, 1965; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Commencement and Hooding Ceremony Programs, 2006-2011; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Commencement and Hooding Ceremony Programs, 2012-2013; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - GWU Law School Commencment, 2003; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Convocation in Honor of President Ronald and Nancy Reagan, 1991; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Stylistic guidelines, 1968-1995; RG0034 Series 2; .25 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series consists of stylistic guidelines. They range in date from 1968-1995.
  Formerly vertical files
  - Office of Academic Publications - Stylistic Guidelines, circa 1968-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Master Course and Program Data Forms, 1975-2004; RG0034 Series 3; George Washington University. Office of Academic Publications; George Washington University. Graduate Studies and Academic Affairs. Academic Publications; 4.5 Linear Feet 3 record cartons
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains files pertaining to the Master Course and Program Data Forms for the Columbian College of Arts and Sciences and for the School of Medicine and Health Sciences. Other subjects include the College of Professional Studies' submission to Middle States (including GWSolutions)and second-class postage permit filings.
  Conditions Governing Access
  This series is unprocessed, and documents are unfoldered. Additional time may be required to access this portion of the collection. Please see Special Collections staff for assistance.
  Publications; George Washington University -- Students
  - Master Course and Program Data Forms (MC/PDFs), 1993-2002; Series 3 (Box 1)
    Arrangement
    Materials are sorted by school/department.
  - Master Course and Program Data Forms (MC/PDFs) for Columbian College of Arts and Sciences: American Studies to Romance, Greek, and Slavic Languages and Literatures., 1998-2004; Series 3 (Box 2)
  - Master Course and Program Data Forms (MC/PDFs) for Columbian College of Arts and Sciences: Sociology to Women's Studies. MC/PDFs for School of Medicine and Health Sciences/MD Program., 1975-2002 (Box 3)
    This box also contains general Master Course and Program Data Forms from the Executive Vice President for Academic Affairs office (1988-1993), College of Professional Studies' initial submission to Middle States including GWSolutions (2000), and GW's second-class postage permit filings (1975-2002)